It's the story of a man, a woman, and a rabbit in a triangle of trouble.
Who Framed Roger Rabbit is a fantasy, animation,
comedy film directed by Robert Zemeckis.
'Toon star Roger is worried that his wife Jessica is playing pattycake with someone
else, so the studio hires detective Eddie Valiant to snoop on her.
But the stakes are quickly raised when Marvin Acme is
found dead and Roger is the prime suspect.
Eddie Valiant, played by Bob Hoskins.
Judge Doom, played by Christopher Lloyd.
Dolores, played by Joanna Cassidy.
Roger Rabbit / Benny The Cab / Greasy / Psycho
(voice), played by Charles Fleischer.
Jessica Rabbit (voice) (uncredited), played by Kathleen Turner.
Marvin Acme, played by Stubby Kaye.
Who Framed Roger Rabbit is a 1988 American fantasy comedy film directed by Robert
Zemeckis from a screenplay written by Jeffrey Price and Peter S.
Combining live-action and animation, it is based on the
1981 novel Who Censored Roger Rabbit?
The film stars Bob Hoskins, Christopher Lloyd, Stubby Kaye, and Joanna
Cassidy, with Charles Fleischer providing the voice of Roger Rabbit.
Set in an alternative history Hollywood in 1947, where humans and cartoon characters (referred to as "toons") co-exist, Who Framed Roger Rabbit
follows Eddie Valiant, a private investigator with a grudge against toons, who must help exonerate Roger, who has been framed for murder.
Walt Disney Studios purchased the film rights for the story in 1981.
Price and Seaman wrote two drafts of the script before Disney brought in executive
producer Steven Spielberg and his production company, Amblin Entertainment.
Zemeckis was brought on to direct, and Canadian-British animator Richard
Williams was hired to supervise the animation sequences.
Production was moved from Los Angeles to Elstree Studios in England
to accommodate Williams and his group of animators.
While filming, the production budget rapidly expanded, and the
shooting schedule ran longer than expected.
Who Framed Roger Rabbit was released through Disney's Touchstone
Pictures banner in the United States on June 22, 1988.
The film received critical acclaim for its visuals, humor, writing,
performances, and groundbreaking combination of live-action and animation.
It grossed over $351 million worldwide, becoming the
second-highest-grossing film of 1988, behind Rain Man.
It brought a renewed interest in the golden age of American animation,
spearheading modern American animation and the Disney Renaissance.
It won three Academy Awards for Best Film Editing, Best Sound Effects Editing and Best Visual Effects
and received a Special Achievement Academy Award for Williams' animation direction.
In 2016, the film was selected for preservation in the United States National Film Registry by the
Library of Congress as "culturally, historically, or aesthetically significant".
The film explores themes of lovesickness, based on novel or
book, falsely accused, movie business, innocence.
The tone is lighthearted and dark.